# Mario Ricardo Domínguez Quiroz

Mexico City Metropolitan Area

darkmarthur@gmail.com

7772948872

linkedin.com/in/mariodquiroz

## **Summary**

I love the tech industry and always look for places with people from all over the world to grow together innovating projects and bringing up creative solutions for worldwide customers. I am specialized in front-end technologies and translate complex requirements into architectures and project plans for teams and customers, in the same way, communicate complex project status or technologies to non-tech customers and teammates.

### **Experience**

#### Product Owner

#### Softtek

Jan 2023 - Present (1 year 1 month)

Guide the customer into building a product that will optimize their operations and white-label it for other companies.

- Translate customer requirements into a product backlog.
- Break down customer processes and operations into versions, releases, epics, and stories.
- Service to the scrum team to achieve product goals.
- Lead workload income for the scrum team.
- Document, wireframe and diagram, customer product ideas, and definitions.

### **Senior Frontend Developer**

#### Softtek

Sep 2021 - Jan 2023 (1 year 5 months)

Architecture, design, and build of an application from scratch for a customs agent company. I am focused to resolve and optimize critical timing business unit flows and connecting with the Mexican service tax administration department (SAT)

React JS | React Hooks | Redux | Material UI | React Query | React Hook Form | Yup | MSW | Jest | Unit Testing | React Testing Library | Cognito | AWS | Figma

# Ø

### Technical Lead Developer

#### Advanced Mankind

Jan 2019 - Sep 2021 (2 years 9 months)

Flutter, React Native, React JS, Angular, Node JS, Google Cloud Platform (Firebase), Google Analytics, Java Spring Boots, MySQL, InVision, Figma, JIRA, Confluence

- Translate customer requirements into digested scrum stories to the development team.
- ❖ Track, integrate, and audit team software development progress of different countries, and centralize documentation.

- Present product iterations to customers.
- ❖ Work with testing teams to diagnose, track and resolve bugs.
- Connect products to Firebase Analytics
- Define project time estimates.
- Deliver production and beta on App Store Connect & Play Store and test.

Customers: Chedraui México, Any Club (FC Dallas)

### Technical Business Analyst

**Emburse Chrome River** 

May 2018 - Sep 2021 (3 years 5 months)

Python | Jenkins | Bash | MySQL | Java | Drools | Groovy | JIRA | Salesforce | Confluence | Kibana | HTML

- ❖ Team leader of the project: Guiding configuration engineers and testers in Ukraine, India, Mexico
- ❖ Upgrade big brand customers configurations from the old platforms built-in flash to the newer platform using the edge Javascript technologies. This involves a lot of challenges, one of them being the differences in functionalities, the current application is way more robust, so a lot of old legacy business rules logic need to be optimized in the process.
- ❖ Play the role of a project manager by talking to the customers directly walking them through the transition process, explaining how the new functionalities would differ from the previous one and always communicating the updates in their configuration.
- ❖ Report bugs/issues in the software application to the concerned teams by talking to Product owners, support team, create JIRAs and track them.
- Identified areas in the process that could be automated
- ❖ Make sure the documentation is up to date in terms of all the steps of the process, troubleshooting issues, differences between the platforms and how to configure the new one efficiently.
- ❖ Come up with complex SQL queries used across the team for better testing and data analysis, and find bugs in the configuration.
- Prepare time estimates for the project.

# Technical Business Analyst

Crossbridge Global Partners Jobs & Career

May 2018 - Oct 2019 (1 year 6 months)

Nearshoring for Chrome River Technologies

# MEAN Stack Developer

Jack Automation Technologies, Inc.

Oct 2018 - Jul 2019 (10 months)

MEAN Stack developer specialized in UI/UX. Focusing on frontend architecture optimization based on Angular IO

### Unity3D VR Developer, Research Collaborator

CENIDET - Centro Nacional de Investigación y Desarrollo Tecnológico

Jan 2018 - Dec 2018 (1 year)

Social Service Intern at National Center for Technological Research and Development (CENIDET).

Development of interactive scenarios for virtual reality application using Unity3D for Oculus Rift & HTC Vive assisting a masters degree thesis

# Web Developer & Emarketing Analyst

Universidad Internacional

Jul 2014 - Feb 2018 (3 years 8 months)

General Task:

- Analysis, design, development, and innovation of technology for the institutional image, advertising campaigns, and information systems.
- Development of Web Applications in Microsoft .NET environment.
- · Web server administration (IIS).
- Google Analytics
- Apply SEO strategies using Google tools for webmasters.
- Maintenance of institutional blogs in WordPress.
- · Development of visual media.
- Customer Service and Technical Support.

### **Education**

### Universidad Internacional

Postgraduate Degree / Especialidad, Computer/Information Technology Administration and Management

2021 - 2022

#### Universidad Autónoma del Estado de Morelos

Diploma of Education, Data Science with Python / Machine Learning

2021 - 2021

Data science diploma issued by UAEM Center for Research in Cognitive Sciences

# Universidad Internacional

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Computer Software Engineering 2014 - 2018

### **Licenses & Certifications**

Visual Communication using Adobe Photoshop® CS6 - Certiport - A Pearson VUE
Business
m7LN-XV99

Web Communication using Adobe Dreamweaver® CS6 - Certiport - A Pearson VUE Business

VOE Dusiness

JwnL-4TA5

- Microsoft Office Excel® 2010 Expert Certiport A Pearson VUE Business wLscz-FME6
- Microsoft Office Word 2010 Expert Certiport A Pearson VUE Business uHSL-XLJq
- Microsoft Office PowerPoint® 2010 Certiport A Pearson VUE Business Un36-s2SD
- CCNA I Switching & Routing Cisco Networking Academy
  Issued Aug 2016 Expires Jan 2017
  44620831
- CCNA II Routing & Switching Cisco Networking Academy
  Issued Jan 2017 Expires Jul 2017
  44620831
- CCNA III Routing and Switching Cisco Networking Academy Issued Sep 2017 Expires Dec 2017 44620831
- CCNA IV Routing and Switching Cisco Networking Academy Issued Jan 2018 Expires Mar 2018 44620831

### **Skills**

Leadership • Project Management • Front-end Development • React Hooks • Material-UI • Team Leadership • Jest • Unit Testing • Amazon Cognito • Figma (Software)